<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>EBSG - Lite</name>
  <author>alite</author>
  <packageId>EBSG.Lite</packageId>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.5</li>
  </supportedVersions>
  
  <modDependencies>
    <li>
      <packageId>ludeon.rimworld.biotech</packageId>
      <displayName>Biotech</displayName>
    </li>
  </modDependencies>

  <loadAfter>
    <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Royalty</li>
    <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Ideology</li>
    <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Biotech</li>
    <li>OskarPotocki.VanillaFactionsExpanded.Core</li>
    <li>vanillaracesexpanded.genie</li>
    <li>SA.Cryoweapons</li>
    <li>SuperheroGenesBase.Mod</li>
    <li>EBSG.Framework</li>
  </loadAfter>

  <description>
Expanded Biotech Style Genes(EBSG) is the step beyond [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2985153870]More Biotech Style Genes[/url]. Where that series sought to expand ranges that already exist, this series seeks to add ranges that should exist. You get gene ranges that alter sleep fall rate, but why not a range for changing the rate it recovers? If you can have fire resistance genes, why not have genes to resist other types of damage like frostbite and acid?

Well now both those questions will be solved, and more. This is a much lighter variation of [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3020821838]Expanded Biotech Style Genes - All in One[/url] that trims that mod down from the over 500 in that mod to a little over 200. If you are looking to replace the All in One, you should start a new save as this removes a lot of the stuff that it its heavier version adds. Most of the genes in this mod are the 2 and 4 met versions of the genes from that mod because they were usually the ones I felt would be of the most interest.

There won't be individual mods for any of the gene types inside this one, nor will there be 1.4 compatability because I haven't tested it and your game should be up to date anyway when starting a new game.

[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3112549163]Please keep in mind that many genes will not appear unless the EBSG Framework is active.[/url]

______________________________________

Certain mods are completely removed from this because there wasn't a way to trim them down, so I felt that leaving it to the player to choose to download the isolated version allows everyone to have a more customized set of genes. This also trims down how many genes get added by [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3039936922]Expanded Archite Genes[/url].

[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3115290386]Environmental Preference Genes[/url]
[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3137774673]Expanded Dependency Genes[/url]
[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3005456521]Expanded Resistance Genes[/url]
[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3137775020]Passion Genes[/url]

If you download another one of the individual mods, that mod will generally add in all the genes that this one doesn't have

______________________________________

[url=https://discord.gg/fYP8qkcNDh]Discord link[/url] for those who want an easier way to ask questions, make requests, or just chat. I'll also be posting new releases there.

[url=https://steamcommunity.com/id/alite/myworkshopfiles/?appid=294100]Easy link to all of my Rimworld mods[/url]

[url=https://github.com/KonradHeinser/ExpandedBiotechStyleGenes][img]https://i.imgur.com/kTkpTOE.png[/img][/url]
[url=https://ko-fi.com/alite56114][img]https://i.imgur.com/Utx6OIH.png[/img][/url]
  </description>
</ModMetaData>

<!--Original textures for gene icons are available on https://game-icons.net-->
